你们都觉得这双鞋很丑吗？ 对
-Does everybody hate these shoes? -Yeah.
别担心，没有人会注意的 只要你穿着那件浴巾装
But nobody will focus on that if you wear that towel-dress.
你跟他说吧
Tell him.
这是她新工作的第一天 你不该一早就开她玩笑
It's her first day at this new job. You shouldn't start with her.
好吧，我可以等到晚上再说
All right. I suppose I can wait a day.
你星期五有节目吗？ 干嘛？
-What are you doing Friday? -Why?
你得来参加我的怪堂哥 艾勃特的告别单身派对
Come to my weird cousin Albert's bachelor party.
你知道，他是植物学家
You know,he's the botanist?
老天
Oh,God!
植物学家都神神经经的
Botanists are such geeks.
那是恐龙领带吗？
Is that a dinosaur tie?
早安
Morning!
瑞秋，我拿皮包来了
Rach,I'm here with the purses!
在这么多包里找钥匙得要一辈子
It must take you forever to find your keys.
谢谢，菲比
Thank you,Pheebs.
不客气，拜托你用 这个乌龟包包
You're welcome. Please want the one with the turtles.
不，乌龟让我害怕 今天尤其不是时候
No,turtles scare me. I don't need that today.
亲爱的，别紧张，没问题的
Honey,just relax. It's gonna be fine.
我过去跟你一起吃午饭吧？
Why don't I come and take you to lunch?
谢了，但马克要带我去吃饭
Thank you! But Mark's taking me out.
马克？就是那个 帮你找工作的马克？
Mark? Is that the same Mark that helped you get the job?
对，算是祝我第一天工作顺利
It's like a "good luck on your first day" thing.
那是午餐盒吗？
Is this a lunch box?
不，是皮包 里面还有个热水瓶
No,a purse. And there's a thermos in it.
你星期五能来吗？ 什么？
-So can you make it on Friday? -What?
我想可以吧 可是你为什么要请我呢？
I think so. Why am I invited to this again?
显然艾勃特没有朋友
Apparently,Albert has no friends.
他对告别单身派对充满期待
He's excited about the bachelor party.
我想他是为了看 脱衣舞娘才结婚的
He's only getting married so he can see a stripper.
请脱衣舞娘参加告别单身派对 你们真是老套
A stripper at a bachelor party. That is so cliche.
为什么不请魔术师？
Why don't you guys get a magician?
如果魔术师可以用臀部 给我开啤酒，那就行
If he can open my beer with his butt-cheeks,then all right.
本集播出：“嫉妒”
The One With All the Jealousy
她要跟她吃午饭？ 跟他吃午饭？
She's having lunch with him? Lunch with him?
你该看看她被录取时 是怎么拥抱他的
You should've seen him hug her when she got the job!
而且他很帅
And he's really good-looking.
我该怎么办？ 不怎么办
-What am I gonna do? -You don't do anything.
放在心里 学着隐藏你的感情
IKeep it inside. Learn how to hide your feelings.
不要大哭
Don't cry out loud.
猜猜谁得到了百老汇 音乐剧的试演机会？
Guess who has an audition for a Broadway musical?
我本来要说是你 不过这个答案好像太容易了
I wanna say you,but it seems like such an easy answer.
就是我
It is me!
这是音乐剧版的“双城记”（狄更斯名著）
It's a musical version of A Tale of Two Cities.
我想我要唱“纽约，纽约”
So I think I'm gonna sing "New York,New York"...
和“我把心留在旧金山”
...and "I Left My Heart in San Francisco."
乔伊，我想轮不到你来挑城市
Joey,I don't think you get to pick the cities.
什么？
What?
这是狄更斯先生的选择
Mr. Dickens gets to pick them.
谁？
Who?
我拿克里夫名著解读给你
I'll get you the Cliff Notes.
什么？
The what?
简易文学读本
The abridgment.
什么？
The what?
型号
Then the style number...
发货号码…和出货日期
...the invoice number and the shipping date.
很好，有问题吗？
Good. Any questions so far?
我们买东西会有多少折扣？
What kind of discount do we get?
八折
Twenty percent.
我爱死这份工作了
I love this job!
我的第一通电话 来，让我代劳
-My first call! -Here,let me.
瑞秋格林的电话，需要我效劳吗？
Rachel Greene's line. May I help you?
嗨，瑞秋在吗？
Hi,is Rachel there?
请问是哪一位？ 我是罗斯
-And who may I say is calling? -This is Ross.
哪位罗斯？
Ross of...?
“罗斯和瑞秋”的罗斯
Of "Ross and Rachel."
嗨，我是马克
Hi,it's Mark.
嘿，马克 嘿
-Hey,Mark. -Hey.
等一下 好
Hold on a second. It's Ross.
嗨，亲爱的
Hi,honey.
马克怎么会替你接电话？
What's Mark doing answering your phone?
他只是在附近闲逛
Oh,he's just goofing around.
有意思
Oh,that's funny.
他干嘛不在自己办公室闲逛？
Why isn't he goofing around in his own office?
这里就是他办公室，我说过 我们是乔安娜的两个助理
This is his office too. I told you,we're Joanna's two assistants.
乔安娜为什么需要两个助理？
Why does Joanna need two assistants?
她很懒吗？
How lazy is she?
我的天，我做了什么？
Oh,my God! What did I just do?
我刚把三千副胸罩 送到人事部去了
I just shipped 3000 bras to Personnel!
我要挂电话了 马克，我需要你
I gotta go! Mark,I need you!
好，再见
Okay! Bye-bye!
对不起，甜心，我只是要…
I'm sorry,sweetie. I was just trying to
我只是要打下一个电话
I was dialing another number.
我30秒钟换好衣服 就是让你跟他独处
I got changed in 30 seconds so you could be alone with him.
你最好赶快展开攻势
You better go for it.
我不要展开什么攻势
I'm not going for anything.
你不要的话，我要
Well,if you don't,I will.
拜托你走吧？
Would you please go?
晚安，莫妮卡
'Night,Mon.
晚安，胡利欧
'Night,Julio.
胡利欧，有人把书忘在这里了
Someone left their book here.
事实上，那是我的书
Actually,that is mine.
你在看什么书？
What are you reading?
波德莱尔的《恶之花》（现代派文学代表作） 你看过没有？
Flowers of Evil,by Baudelaire. Have you read it?
我看过没有？
Have I read it?
没有，你喜欢吗？
No. Are you enjoying it?
我本来以为我会喜欢 不过翻译得不好
I thought I would,but the translation's no good.
你是诗人，居然不懂
You're a poet and you don't know it.
其实，我…
Actually,l....
我是诗人
I am a poet.
那你一定懂了
So you do know it.
你都写些什么？
So what kind of things do you write about?
写一些让我感动的事物
Things that move me:
婆娑树影
The shadow of a tree...
童稚笑容
...a child laughing...
或这片嘴唇
...or this lip.
我的？
Mine?
这里？
Right here?
我可以为这片嘴唇写一部史诗
I could write an epic poem about this lip.
要怎么写？
How would that go?
虽然没有押韵…
Well,it didn't rhyme...
不过我喜欢
...but I liked it.
你们得扒一、两个钱包
You've got to pick a pocket or two...
孩子们…
...boys
你得扒一、两个…
You've got to pick a pocket...
钱包…
... or two
真好
Lovely.
太好了
Just lovely.
真的？谢谢
Really? Thanks.
乔伊，我们非常希望 星期六再看到你
We definitely want to see you for the callback on Saturday.
太好了
Excellent!
我会来的
I'll be there.
别忘了带你的爵士舞鞋 来参加舞蹈试演
Don't forget to bring your jazz shoes for the dance audition.
我的经纪人说 这个角色不必跳舞
My agent said that it wasn't a dancing part.
所有的角色都要跳一点舞
All the roles gotta dance a little.
但以你的舞蹈背景 小意思罢了
But with your dance background,it'll be a piece of cake.
追随特维拉撒普（著名现代舞指导）学习三年现代舞？
"Three years of modern dance with Twyla Tharp"?
在美国芭蕾舞团待了五年？
"Five years with the American Ballet Theatre"?
谁的履历表不作假？
Everybody lies on their resume,okay?
我也不是“《光圈》之子”（摄影杂志）中的一员
I wasn't one of the Zoom kids either.
你到底会不会跳舞？
Well,can you,like,dance at all?
我会跳舞，你知道…
Yeah,I can dance. You know....
这是干什么？
What is that?
现在看起来很蠢 因为没有放音乐
Sure,it looks stupid now. There's no music playing.
我得去接电话 不过，不要…
I have to get that. But,no,no.
嗨
Hi.
听我说，我需要个脱衣舞娘 我听说你是跳脱衣舞的
Listen,I'm in need of a stripper and I was told that you do that.
我问你，你多收一百块 可以额外提供什么服务？
Let me ask you this. What do you do for the extra hundred?
那我要提供葡萄吗？
So would I have to provide the grapes?
嗨
Hi.
你昨晚跟胡利欧约会的情况怎么样，小姐（西班牙语）？
How was last night with Julio,senorita?
简直不可思议，他性感又聪明 这让他显得更性感
It was amazing. He's sexy and smart,which makes him even sexier.
我得告诉你 昨晚我们亲热的时候…
Last night we were fooling around...
突然之间，他停下来写诗…
...and all of a sudden he stops to write a poem.
少来了，我就算被 陨石打中也停不下来
Get out! I couldn't stop if a meteor hit me.
我们请了脱衣舞娘 “水晶吊灯小姐”
We have our stripper,a "Miss Crystal Chandelier."
从小就取这种名字 长大了还能做什么？
Name a kid that,what do you expect them to grow up to be?
但他忘了把这首诗带走
But he forgot to take the poem with him.
我看不懂诗 不过我觉得这是一首好诗
I am totally dense about poetry,but I think this is pretty good.
你们看看
Check it out.
“空花瓶” 半透明的美
"The Empty Vase. Translucent beauty"
不要念出声
To yourself.
写得很好
You know,that's pretty good.
对，我也觉得，菲比？
Yeah,I think so too. Phoebe?
太棒了 我真高兴你们都喜欢
Great! I'm so glad you guys like it!
我得去上班了 我还没看完
-I gotta go to work. -I'm not done.
看完再还给我
Give it back when you're through.
回头见 再见
-See you guys. -Bye-bye.
我的天…可怜的莫妮卡
Oh,my God! Oh,my God! Poor Monica!
怎么了？…
What? What? What?
他在跟她亲热的时候写这首诗
He was with her when he wrote this poem!
我的花瓶如此美丽 内里空无一物
"My vessel so lovely,with nothing inside"?
如今我伸手触摸 你看似更加空洞
"Now that I've touched you,you seem emptier still"?
他觉得莫妮卡很空洞 她是个空花瓶
He thinks Monica's empty. She's the empty vase!
-空花瓶，空花瓶？-莫妮卡不是空花瓶
-Vase, vase?-Monica's not an empty vase.
你认为她是花瓶？
You think vase?
你真的觉得他是这个意思？
You really think he meant that?
一点都没错
Totally.
老天，她看起来好幸福
Oh,God! And she seems so happy too.
看完了
Done.
怎么了
What happened?
乔伊，你认为这首诗的含义是什么
Joey, what do you think this poem means?
莫妮卡是花瓶，对吧
Monica's the vase, right?
你真是深不可测
You are such a mystery to me.
我是如此爱你
你有罗夫罗兰的档案吗？
Do you have the Ralph Lauren file?
当然有，就在
Oh,yeah,sure! It's right
那是什么？
What's that?
是罗斯送的，爱的金龟
It's from Ross. It's a Love Bug.
他想向全世界宣告 你已经有男朋友了
Somebody wants people to know you have a boyfriend.
他不是这个意思
That's not what he's doing.
他只是非常浪漫罢了
He's just really romantic.
对不起，你是瑞秋格林吗？
Excuse me. Are you Rachel Greene?
1、2、3
One,two,three.
恭喜你新工作的第一周
Congratulations on your first week At your brand-new job
要不了多久你就会当老板了
It won't be long Before you're the boss
你知道到时候 谁会支持你
And you know who will be there To support you
就是你唯一的男朋友
Your one and only boyfriend
有男朋友真好
It's nice to have a boyfriend!
你忠心、深情的男友，罗斯
Your loyal,loving boyfriend,Ross!
我伤心，我真得很伤心…
I'm hurt! I'm actually hurt...
你居然以为我送那些东西 不是出于对你的爱
...that you'd think I'd send those things out of anything but love.
伤心
Hurt!
好，我懂了，你很伤心
All right,I get it. You're hurt!
男人不能请理发店四重唱…
Can't a guy send a barbershop quartet...
到女朋友的办公室吗？
...to his girlfriend's office anymore?
拜托，罗斯 这实在太明显了
Oh,please! It was so obvious...
你好像在划定地盘
...Iike you were marking your territory.
你干脆到办公室来 在我的桌子周围撒尿好了
You might as well have just come in and peed around my desk!
我绝对不会这么做
I would never do that.
听我说，我知道这是怎么回事
Look,I know what's going on here.
马克都跟我解释过了 他说你们男人就是这样
Mark explained it all to me. He said this is what you guys do.
如果马克这么说 那马克就是白痴
Well,if Mark said that,then Mark's an idiot.
马克是个天才
Mark's a genius.
为什么？怎么说？ 他为什么会是天才？
Why? How? How is he a genius?
你还看不出来吗？
Don't you see what's happening?
他没有勾引她 反而当了她的知己
Instead of hitting on her now,he's becoming her confidante.
现在她就会跑去跟他抱怨你
Now he's gonna be the guy she goes to,to complain about you.
你还好吧
You okay over there?
我今天去上了舞蹈课，好应付明天的复试
l tried taking a dance class today to get ready for this callback tomorrow.
-怎么样？-撞倒了一个女孩
-How'd it go?-Knocked over a girl.
干得好 回到马克的话题好吗 我该怎么办？
Good work. Can we get back to the Mark thing?What am I gonna do?
何不送她一个音乐金龟？
Why don't you send her a musical bug?
不，你已经送过了
No,you already did that.
你得亲自过去
You're gonna have to go there yourself now.
给她一个惊喜的来访
Make a few surprise visits.
我不知道
I don't know,guys.
很好，不要轻举妄动 坐着跟我们聊天
Fine,don't do anything. Sit and talk to us.
这时候她正在跟他谈你
Meanwhile,she is talking to him about you.
他是体帖入微先生
And he's being Mr. Joe Sensitive.
她在想“也许他就是我的伴侣 他这么了解我”
She's thinking,"Maybe he's the guy for me because he understands me."
你还没搞清楚状况 她就跟他在一起了
And before you know it,she's with him.
你就会说“老天”
And you'll be all,"Oh,man!"
他会说“太棒了”
And he'll be all,"Yes!"
我们都会说“傻瓜”
And us,we'll be like,"Oh,dude!"
很快你就会说…
And pretty soon you'll be like:
“嗨”
"Hi."
还有“我不能去 瑞秋和马克可能在那里”
And,"Well,I can't go. Rachel and Mark might be there."
我们会说“忘了吧 已经四年了”
And we'll be like,"Man,get over it! It's been four years!"
他说得很有画面感，不是吗？
He paints quite a picture,doesn't he?
这是谢莉西格尔（加拿大唱片公司老板）12月的材料
Here's the Shelley Segal stuff for December.
等等，我有东西要给你
Wait,I've got something for you.
没关系，瑞秋知道
It's okay. Rachel knows.
对，但就算是这样…
Yeah,but even so
我控制不了，我为你疯狂
I can't help it. I'm just crazy about you.
你真会讲话
Oh,that is so sweet!
我知道我老是做不得体的事 但是这真的好难
I know I'm Mr. Inappropriate today,but it's just so tough.
看着你走来走去 我好想把你抱在怀里
I see you walking around,and I want to touch and hold you....
来，这里没有人，吻我吧
Come on,no one's around. Just kiss me.
好了，够了，放开她
All right,that's it! Get off of her!
怎么回事？
What is going on?
怎么回事？ 我告诉你这是怎么回事
What's going on? I'll tell you what's going on!
我在你们公司 找领带找了20分钟
I have been down in your store for 20 minutes,trying to get a tie.
要怎么样才有人来服务我？
What do I have to do to get some service?
嗨，瑞秋
Hi,Rach.
乔伊崔比亚尼
Joey Tribbiani?
现在出了问题
I've got a problem.
舞蹈领队打电话来
I just got a call from my dance captain.
他感情出现危机 不能离开长岛
He's having a relationship crisis and can't leave Long lsland.
这表示试演取消了吗？
Does that mean the audition's off?
既然你的经验丰富
Seeing as you've got the most experience...
我希望你来领舞
... I want you to teach these dancers the combination.
什么？
What?
好啦，很简单嘛 你知道，就是手…
Come on,it's easy. You know,it's hand,hand...
头…
... head,head...
抬起来…不要挤在一起…
... up,pas de bourree,pas de bourree...
大旋转…腿转圈…
... big turn here,rond de jambe....
滑过来，一步，再一步…
Slide,step,step...
爵士手势
...and jazz hands!
这么说是踏步舞步和爵士手势
So that's,"Steppity-step and jazz hands."
跳得高兴点
Have fun.
再见
Bye.
你在包什么？
What are you wrapping?
看我送胡利欧什么？
Look what I got Julio.
是个花瓶
It's a vase.
就像他那首诗
Just like the one in the poem.
不完全跟那首诗一样
Not exactly like the one in the poem.
此话怎讲？
What do you mean?
记得你说过你不会看诗吗？
Remember how you said you were really dense about poetry?
这么说我只是个空洞的花瓶？
So I'm just an empty vase?
什么？
What?
好，我不像你那样常看名著
So,I don't read as many important books as you do.
我也不写表里不一的怪诗
And I don't write trick poems that aren't about what they seem.
我喜欢愚蠢的东西
And I get excited about stupid stuff...
就像我的时人杂志来的时候…
...Iike when my People magazine comes...
还有《全部拥有》商品型录来的时候…
...and the new "Hold Everything" catalog.
但这不表示我是空洞的 我关心我的家人和朋友
But that doesn't mean I'm empty. I care about things. Friends and family.
你没有权利批判我 你根本不了解我
You have no right to judge me! You don't even know me!
这首诗讲的不是你
The poem is not about you.
什么？
What?
“空花瓶”讲的不是你
"The Empty Vase" is not about you.
我亲爱的宝贝…
My baby preciosa....
你居然这么想，我好难过
You make me so sad that you would think this.
对不起，这…
I'm sorry. It's....
我朋友菲比说…
My friend Phoebe said
这是讲所有的女人
It's about all women.
应该是说…
Well...
全美国的女人
...all American women.
好受点了没有？
You feel better now?
好，来吧
All right,let's do it.
那是什么玩意儿？
What was that?
他们最多只能跳到这个程度
It's the best I could get out of them.
各位…
Well,people!
People,people,people!
我们再试一次 这次大家好好看着乔伊
Let's try it again. And this time,everybody watch Joey.
教他们怎么跳
Show 'em how it's done.
弹琴，麦克
Count it off,Mack.
“中央咖啡厅”
你昨晚参加告别单身派对 玩得开心吗？
Did you have fun at the bachelor party last night?
看我拿到什么？ 看，她穿着衣服，对吗？
Look what I got! See,she's dressed,right?
然后按一下 她裸体了
And then you click it,and uh-oh,she's naked!
然后再按一下 她又穿上衣服了
And then you click it again and she's dressed.
她是个做生意的女人 走在大街上
She's a business woman walking down the street.
她在逛橱窗 哦，她裸体了
She's window shopping,and oh,she's naked!
我要跟这只笔独处一阵子
I'm gonna spend some alone time with the pen.
对不起，我是个白痴
I'm sorry. I was an idiot.
大白痴
A big idiot.
你必须了解…
It's just,you have to realize...
我很难接受马克这件事…
...this Mark thing is hard for me.
为什么？我们在一起快一年了
Why is it hard? We've been together for almost a year now.
我跟卡萝在一起八年了
Well,I was with Carol for,like,eight years.
而我失去了她
And I lost her.
现在，如果有这个可能 我想我爱你比爱她更深
And now,if it's possible,I think I love you even more.
所以我很难相信我不会…
So it's hard for me to believe I'm not gonna...
别人不会把你夺走…
...well,that someone else isn't gonna take you away.
让我夺走她吧…
Let it be me. Let it be me!
亲爱的，你的话好贴心
Honey,that's very sweet.
我只是觉得 如果两个人彼此相爱
It just seems to me,though,that if two people love each other...
彼此信任，像我们这样
...and trust each other,like we do...
就没有理由嫉妒
...there's no reason to be jealous.
我得走了
I gotta get going.
再见，钱德
Bye,Chandler.
这枝笔有点无聊了 可以帮我拿几本色情杂志吗？
This pen's getting kind of boring. Can you pick me up some porn?
你要去哪里？
Where you going?
我得去接班 带他跟别人出去玩
I've gotta go pick up Ben for a play-date this afternoon.
跟谁？
With who?
跟我昨晚在派对上认识的女人
Just this woman I met last night at the party.
昨晚派对的女人…
There was a woman at?
脱衣舞娘？
The stripper?
你跟脱衣舞娘一起出去玩？
You have a play-date with a stripper?
老天，我得生个孩子才行
Man,I gotta get a kid!
她跳完脱衣舞之后 我们开始聊天
We started talking after she did her thing...
她有个和班年龄相仿的儿子
...and she's got a boy about Ben's age.
我们要带孩子去上金宝贝早教课
So we're gonna take the kids to a Gymboree class.
可以吗？ 当然可以，她结婚没有？
-ls that okay? -Sure. Is she married?
你嫉妒吗？
Are you jealous?
我不懂她干嘛跟你出去玩
I just don't see why she has to play with you.
她没有其他当妈妈的 脱衣舞娘朋友吗？
I mean,doesn't she have any other stripper-mom friends of her own?
你嫉妒得要命
You are totally jealous!
我才没有嫉妒
I'm not jealous.
这是因为…
This is about...
人们对脱衣舞娘…
... people feeling certain things...
都有某种…
...you know,about...
看法，你知道…
...strippers. And,you know....
我也爱你
I love you too.
再见
Bye.
等等…
Wait,wait,wait!
干嘛？
What?
这个吻可以让他 回味好几个小时
Well,there's a kiss he won't forget for a few hours.
或者，你刚煽起他的火来 反而便宜了脱衣舞娘
Either that or you just turned him on and sent him to a stripper.
好吧，我嫉妒了，我嫉妒了
All right, l'm jealous.l'm jealous!
“哦，钱德，请不要这样，我求求你不要…”
''Oh, no. Chandler, please don't.No, l beg of you to not--''
胡利欧在这里吗？
Is there a Julio here?
我就是胡利欧
I am Julio.
你非常自以为是
Mr. Pretentious
以为自己好得不得了 你的诗都没出版
You think there's no one finer Your poems are unpublished
你在餐厅工作
And you work in a diner
你不是上帝对女人的恩赐 这只是你自以为是
You're no God's gift to women That's all in your head
你只是个马屁精
You are just a butt-munch
没人喜欢马屁精
No one likes a butt-munch!
你的床上工夫也很烂
And you're also bad in bed